# Fellippe Bione Geologist (DSc)

Rua Mem de Sá, 81, Niterói – RJ, Brazil +55 (21) 97549-2442 fbione@id.uff.br https://www.linkedin.com/in/frbione/ https://github.com/frbione

Languages: Portuguese (native) | English (fluent) | Spanish (intermediate)

## **Profile**

A professional with five years of experience in geoscientific software development projects (R&D), looking forward to solving scientific-industrial problems by developing creative solutions through highly adaptive and proactive work. I have large experience in working at multidisciplinary projects for technological innovation, especially those related to geological modeling and applied research. I am always curious about learning new topics and open to new challenges.

### **Education**

**DOCTORAL DEGREE IN GEOSCIENCES** | 2024 | UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL FLUMINENSE

MASTER DEGREE IN GEOLOGY | 2019 | UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DO RIO DE JANEIRO

**DEGREE IN GEOLOGY** | 2016 | UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DO RIO DE JANEIRO

# **Professional Experience**

#### SENIOR GEOSCIENTIST @ ELIIS | AUGUST 2024 - PRESENT

- · Geological consultancy;
- · R&D and Project Management (database related Petrobras);
- · Project proposals;
- · Algorithm development (PaleoScan™ Python Extension);
- · Events presentations;
- · Software testing;

#### GEOLOGIST @ PETROSOFT DESIGN | NOVEMBER 2021 - AUGUST 2024

- · Geological consultancy;
- · Algorithm development and project proposals;
- Meeting with company's decision-makers to align needs and maximize the integration of proposed solutions to the main framework;
- · Software testing and QA/QC;
- · Client support;
- · Scientific and technical report writing.

#### RESEARCHER @ LOOP - UFF | MARCH 2019 - DECEMBER 2022

- · Data interpretation, spatialization and modeling (well log, seismic and geochemical data);
- · Software development team management, conceptual model, code writing (Python);
- · Sequence stratigraphy and 3D stratigraphic modeling (Espírito Santo Basin);
- · Mentoring undergraduate students of different areas (geology, geophysics and computer sciences).

## **Skills**

- · Geological modeling:
- · Stratigraphy;
- · Seismic data;
- · Geoprocessing;
- · Data science:
- · Geophysics;
- · Team management;

- · Python:
- · Machine Learning;
- · Version control (git);
- · G&G software:
- · Problem-solving:
- · Team-working;
- · Agile developments.

# **Courses and Certificates**

DATA ANALYSIS WITH PYTHON | 2021 | IBM - COURSERA | 13 h

EXPLORATORY DATA ANALYSIS FOR MACHINE LEARNING | 2021 | IBM - COURSERA | 8 h

DIONISOSFLOW TRAINING | 2021 | IFP ENERGIES NOUVELLES | 6 h

STRATIGRAPHIC FORWARD MODELLING: A SHORT INTRODUCTION TO DIONISOSFLOW | 2019 | IFP ENERGIES NOUVELLES | 16 h

**OFFSHORE DRILLING TECHNIQUES** | 2016 | TOTAL PROFESSEURS ASSOCIÉS and TOTAL E&P DO BRASIL | 20 H

# **Registered Patents**

Albuquerque, A.L.S., Venancio, I.M., **Bione, F.R.A.**, Abreu, P.V., Couto, L.L., Moreira, M., Bernardes, M.C., Belem, A.L., Santos, T.P., Díaz, R., Souza, I.V.A.F., Spigolón, A,L,D. 2021. **Método de determinação do conteúdo, qualidade e maturação da matéria orgânica em ambiente marinho para exploração de poços de petróleo.** Instituto Nacional da Propriedade Industrial, Brazil. Depositors: Petróleo Brasileiro S.A., Federal Fluminense University. Attorney: Francisco Carlos Rodrigues Silva. BR 102021025711-3 A2, 2023. Deposit date: December 18th 2021. National Publication date: June 20th **2023**.

Albuquerque, A.L.S., Venancio, I.M., **Bione, F.R.A.**, Abreu, P.V., Couto, L.L., Moreira, M., Bernardes, M.C., Belem, A.L., Santos, T.P., Díaz, R., Souza, I.V.A.F., Spigolón, A.L.D. 2021. **Method for determining the content, quality and maturation of organic matter in marine environment for exploration of oil wells**. United States Patent and Trademark Office, United States. Patent: Utility model. Registry number: US2023/0195966A1, 2023. Deposit date: December 19th 2022. Publication date: June 22nd **2023**. Financing institutions: Petróleo Brasileiro S.A., Federal Fluminense University.

# **Scientific Publications**

Bione, F.R.A. et al. Estimating total organic carbon of potential source rocks in the Espírito Santo Basin, SE Brazil, using XGBoost. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 162, 106765, 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2024.106765

Santos, T.P., Lisboa, L.P., Carreira, V., **Bione, F.R.A.**, Venancio, I.M., Bernardes, M.C., Belem, A.L., Díaz, R., Moreira, M., Lopes, A.A.O, Santos, T.L., Souza, I.V., Spigolon, A.L.D., Albuquerque, A.L.S. **Orbitally-driven Paleogene to Neogene deposition in the western South Atlantic (Espírito Santo Basin) and its correlation with global sea level. Sedimentology, <b>2023**. https://doi.org/10.1111/sed.13104

Venancio, I.M., Santos, T.P., **Bione, F.R.A.**, Belem, A.L., Bernardes, M.C., Díaz, R., Moreira, M., Carreira, V., Spigolon, A., Souza, I.V.A.F., Albuquerque, A.L.S. **Preservation Factors during Cretaceous Oceanic Anoxic Events in the Espírito Santo Basin, Southeast Brazil**. Geosciences, 12(10), 251, **2022**. https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences12100351

Venancio, I.M., Belem, A.L., Santos, T.P., Lessa, D.O., **Bione, F.R.A.**, Díaz, R., Bernardes, M.C., Souza, I.V.A.F., Coutinho, L.F.C., Albuquerque, A.L.S. **Temporal and spatial differences between predicted and measured organic carbon in South Atlantic sediments: constraints to organic facies modelling**. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 138, 105524, **2022**. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2022.105524

Santos T.P., **Bione F.R.A.**, Venancio I.M., Bernardes M.C., Belem A.L., Lisboa L.P., Franco D.R., Díaz R.A., Moreira M., Leonardo N.F., Souza I.V., Albuquerque A.L.S. **Late Cretaceous astrochronology, organic carbon evolution, and paleoclimate inferences for the subtropical western South Atlantic, <b>Espírito Santo Basin**. Cretaceous Research, 129, 105032, **2021**. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cretres.2021.105032

Bione, F.R.A. et al., 2019. Geochemistry, Sm-Nd isotopes and SHRIMP U-Pb geochronology of the Morro do Coco Granite (RJ, Brazil): another piece of the post-collisional magmatism of the Ribeira Belt. Braz. J. Geol., 49(3): e20190010. http://dx.doi.org/10.1590/2317-4889201920190010.